export const chapter = "Chapter - 27: Parliamentary Form of Government ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Who ruled India prior to 1947 for about eight centuries?",
        optionA: "Native kings",
        optionB: "Invaders",
        optionC: "Colonialists",
        correctAnswer: "B. Invaders",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the reason for people's desire for independence in India?",
        optionA: "To gain power through force",
        optionB: "To have their own rulers and well-being looked after",
        optionC: "To continue the rule of invaders",
        correctAnswer:
          "B. To have their own rulers and well-being looked after",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which uprising against the rulers in India was the most massive?",
        optionA: "Uprising against the Muslim rulers",
        optionB: "Uprising against the British in 1857",
        optionC: "Uprising against the Indian National Congress",
        correctAnswer: "B. Uprising against the British in 1857",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary reason for choosing a parliamentary form of government in India?",
        optionA: "Centralized power with the President",
        optionB: "Real power vested in the Council of Ministers",
        optionC: "Ruler's absolute authority",
        correctAnswer: "B. Real power vested in the Council of Ministers",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which house of the Indian Parliament is directly elected by the people?",
        optionA: "Lok Sabha",
        optionB: "Rajya Sabha",
        optionC: "President's House",
        correctAnswer: "A. Lok Sabha",
      },
      {
        question: "Who is the ex-officio Chairman of the Rajya Sabha?",
        optionA: "Prime Minister",
        optionB: "Vice President",
        optionC: "President of India",
        correctAnswer: "B. Vice President",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary responsibility of the President of India?",
        optionA: "Implementing laws",
        optionB: "Making laws",
        optionC: "Representing the head of state",
        correctAnswer: "C. Representing the head of state",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which organ of the government is responsible for making laws?",
        optionA: "Legislature",
        optionB: "Executive",
        optionC: "Judiciary",
        correctAnswer: "A. Legislature",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In India, what happens if the Prime Minister and his Council of Ministers lose the majority in the Lok Sabha?",
        optionA: "They continue in office until the next general elections",
        optionB: "They resign from their positions",
        optionC: "The President appoints a new Prime Minister",
        correctAnswer: "B. They resign from their positions",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary role of the President of India in the government?",
        optionA: "To make laws",
        optionB: "To control the government",
        optionC: "To enjoy real power",
        correctAnswer: "B. To control the government",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "India was ruled by invaders for about ______ centuries prior to 1947.",
        options: ["Eight", "Five", "Three"],
        answer: "Eight",
      },
      {
        question:
          "People in India felt the need for independence because they wanted their own people to rule over them and look after their ______.",
        options: ["Interests", "Well-being", "Wealth"],
        answer: "Well-being",
      },
      {
        question: "The Indian National Congress was formed in ______.",
        options: ["1857", "1885", "1947"],
        answer: "1885",
      },
      {
        question: "India chose a ______ form of government.",
        options: ["Presidential", "Parliamentary", "Monarchical"],
        answer: "Parliamentary",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In a parliamentary form of government, the real power is vested in the ______.",
        options: ["President", "Council of Ministers", "Prime Minister"],
        answer: "Council of Ministers",
      },
      {
        question: "The Parliament comprises members elected by ______.",
        options: ["The President", "The Council of Ministers", "The people"],
        answer: "The people",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The parliamentary form of government can be unstable because the Council of Ministers has to resign if any of its actions is rejected by the ______.",
        options: ["President", "Judiciary", "Parliament"],
        answer: "Parliament",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The opposition often tries to bring down the government in a parliamentary form of government, leading to an element of ______.",
        options: ["Stability", "Instability", "Neutrality"],
        answer: "Instability",
      },
      {
        question: "The Prime Minister controls the ______.",
        options: ["Judiciary", "Parliament", "Executive"],
        answer: "Executive",
      },
      {
        question:
          "India is a ______, so the position of the President is unique.",
        options: ["Monarchy", "Republic", "Dictatorship"],
        answer: "Republic",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The Preamble to the Constitution of India incorporates the vision and aspirations of the Indian people.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "India is a sovereign nation, which means it can make laws without interference from other countries.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Secularism in India means that the state gives equal importance to all religions.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In a democratic government, elected representatives are the supreme power.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The President of India is the head of both the nation and the government.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question: "The Indian Constitution has a total of 500 Articles.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Fundamental Duties were included in the Indian Constitution in 1976.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Directive Principles of State Policy can be enforced by the Judiciary.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "India is a federal nation, which means powers are divided among the central government, state government, and local self-government.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Constitution of India came into force on August 15, 1947.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
